Hi, I'm Amy Erinberger. I'm with Option Model Management. I've been a commercial model for many, many years. Some of the tools that a model needs always are for the ladies, you need to have a make-up bag.
You need to be able to do full make-up and hair whenever the client requests it.
This is a common request.
Especially lately it seems like not as many clients are budgeting for hair and make-up artists.
So be prepared to know how to do this yourself.
And men, you should know how to make your hair look good and take care of your skin and teeth just like women do.
Inner beauty, I talked about earlier, but that's a really important thing.
Being comfortable with yourself is a huge tool.
Confidence is a major benefit to your work.
So bring that with you on every job you have.
And be consistent.
Get to know your clients.
Make that, get them to know you a little bit so they feel comfortable working with you.
You'll often be asked to bring certain shoes, maybe a pair of heels that blend in with your skin or a pair of heels that are black, something that will work with the clothing, or even individual clothing items themselves.
This will always be clear in advance of a job.
But having a wardrobe is a nice thing to present yourself and also because you may need it from time to time on your shoots.
Other tools, I would say, I think I might have covered most of it.
Oh, I know that women are required to have nude underwear and men as well.
You need to have something that's not going to be very visible under the clothing.
It's especially important for women because you'll wear much more thin fabrics and things like that, so you have to have nude thongs and bras.
Something that some people may not expect when they get into modeling, but it is important.